export const chapter = "Chapter - 4: The First Cities ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the Chalcolithic Age characterized by?",
        options: [
          "Surplus of food production",
          "Use of advanced technology",
          "Nomadic lifestyles",
        ],
        answer: "Surplus of food production",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In which part of India was copper replaced by iron directly during the transition to metal tools?",
        options: ["North India", "South India", "Central India"],
        answer: "South India",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the significant development that occurred when tin was mixed with copper?",
        options: [
          "The discovery of bronze",
          "The invention of written language",
          "The creation of advanced pottery",
        ],
        answer: "The discovery of bronze",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What allowed people during the Chalcolithic Age to engage in various crafts and occupations besides farming?",
        options: [
          "The use of stone tools",
          "Surplus food production",
          "A nomadic lifestyle",
        ],
        answer: "Surplus food production",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which term is used to describe the civilization that developed in the Indian subcontinent during the Chalcolithic Age?",
        options: [
          "Indus Valley Civilization",
          "Gangetic Civilization",
          "Chalcolithic Society",
        ],
        answer: "Indus Valley Civilization",
      },
      {
        question: "What were the two main cities of the Harappan Civilization?",
        options: [
          "Lahore and Karachi",
          "Harappa and Mohenjodaro",
          "Chotanagpur and Brahmagiri",
        ],
        answer: "Harappa and Mohenjodaro",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which building in the Harappan citadel area might have been the residence of a ruler or oligarchy?",
        options: ["Granaries", "Assembly hall", "Palace-like structure"],
        answer: "Palace-like structure",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the purpose of the Great Bath in the Harappan citadel?",
        options: ["Public hearings", "Religious ceremonies", "A public bath"],
        answer: "A public bath",
      },
      {
        question: "What was the purpose of Harappan seals?",
        options: [
          "To mark territory boundaries",
          "To pack bags and containers",
          "To create artwork",
        ],
        answer: "To pack bags and containers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What factors are believed to have contributed to the mysterious decline of the Harappan Civilization?",
        options: [
          "Invasions, drought, and river course changes",
          "Urbanization, trade, and culture",
          "Nomadic migrations and technological advancements",
        ],
        answer: "Invasions, drought, and river course changes",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Chalcolithic Age, characterized by a surplus of food production, allowed people to engage in trades and occupations other than farming. It marked the transition from stone to __________ tools, which were stronger and more versatile.",
        options: ["Bronze", "Iron", "Metal"],
        correctAnswer: "Metal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In North India, during the Chalcolithic Age, stone tools were replaced by __________, while iron came much later.",
        options: ["Copper", "Bronze", "Zinc"],
        correctAnswer: "Copper",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The transition from stone to metal tools was a significant step as metal tools helped people do their work more skillfully and ably, allowing them to show their skills in various __________.",
        options: ["Crafts", "Pottery", "Farming"],
        correctAnswer: "Crafts",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chalcolithic Age is sometimes referred to as the Copper-Stone Age because both copper and stone were in use. When copper was mixed with tin, it resulted in the creation of __________, which was harder and suitable for making tools and weapons.",
        options: ["Iron", "Bronze", "Steel"],
        correctAnswer: "Bronze",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chalcolithic Age marked the transition from a period of no-records to a period of written-records, as language in its written and spoken form was used more extensively, and people began to engage in various trades and occupations beyond __________.",
        options: ["Farming", "Crafts", "Mining"],
        correctAnswer: "Farming",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The traces of the Chalcolithic Age have been found in various regions, including the Gangetic valley, Chotanagpur plateau, Brahmagiri in Karnataka, and __________ in Maharashtra.",
        options: ["Harappa", "Mohenjodaro", "Navdatoli"],
        correctAnswer: "Navdatoli",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Harappan Civilization, also known as the Indus Valley Civilization, flourished around 4700 years ago in the Indus valley, with two major cities, __________ and Mohenjodaro, located in what is now Pakistan.",
        options: ["Lahore", "Harappa", "Delhi"],
        correctAnswer: "Harappa",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the Harappan citadel area, the important buildings included granaries, an assembly hall, a palace-like structure, workshops, and the Great Bath. The granaries were used to store large amounts of grains for emergencies such as natural disasters and __________.",
        options: ["Famine", "Floods", "Earthquakes"],
        correctAnswer: "Floods",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The lower town of the Harappan cities, where common people lived, consisted of houses made of bricks, mortar, lime, and gypsum, with open roof-tops and __________ for ventilation.",
        options: ["Windows", "Courtyards", "Balconies"],
        correctAnswer: "Windows",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Harappan seals, made from clay, soapstone, or copper, served an important purpose in packing bags and containers to ensure the safety of the goods inside. They often featured depictions of animals, including the mythical creature __________.",
        options: ["Elephant", "Unicorn", "Tiger"],
        correctAnswer: "Unicorn",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The Chalcolithic Age is also known as the Bronze Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Metal tools completely replaced stone tools during the Chalcolithic Age.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The first metal found in India was iron.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Bronze is an alloy made by mixing copper and tin.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Great Bath in the Harappan civilization was primarily used for religious ceremonies.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Harappan civilization was located in what is now modern-day India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Harappan seals were primarily used for agricultural purposes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The climate in the Democratic Republic of Congo is characterized by a cold and dry season.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chalcolithic Age marked the transition from a period of no-records to a period of written records.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The mysterious decline of the Harappan Civilization is well understood and attributed to a single cause.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
